In this next lecture, we're going to give our player character a limited amount of apples.
Right now, if I just spend the XP, I can spawn as many apples as I want.
We're going to make it so our player character has a limited amount of apples.
So if we go back to our player blueprint, I want us to create a new variable and call it apples.
Make this verbal type of an integer.
Then if you create another variable and call it Macs apples.
I then wanted to compile and under Mac apples type in 30 or the maximum amount of apples that you want
your player character to have.
I'm just going to have this be 30 then under apples type in the number of apples on your player character
to start off with.
I'm going to type in five.
Next, we're only going to make our pick out to spoon an apple.
If they have enough apples.
So to do this, if we're dragging our apples and if we get apples and we need to check that this is
greater than zero, because if this is greater than zero, that means we have some apples to throw that
struggle here and look for branch and connect all these nodes.
So if we have more than zero apples, we'll spawn an apple after we spin an apple.
We need to tell the game that we have one less apple.
So in order to do this, we can just drag in our apples, look for apples, and just drag up here.
Look for decrement, hit, decrement, and we'll basically subtract the number of apples that we have
by one.
Then if we drag in our apples and look for apples and just connect this all here.
So now I go compile and go play.
I should be able to spawn by apples.
So let's test this out.
One, two, three, four, five.
So I can only five apples and then I'm apples.
So currently it's kind of hard for the player to tell how many apples they have.
So if we go back to our player, HUD, so if we go to the Widget blueprint and to the player HUD, we're
basically going to create a HUD which will show them our apples that our player character has under
pallet.
Look for a vertical box and just drag this somewhere in here.
Then I want you to look for a horizontal box.
And just drag and place this inside the vertical box.
Next, I want you to look for an image.
And just drag this image inside the horizontal box.
And then if you just select the image and make the image, the apple image that we imported earlier.
You can adjust the size of the image by changing the image size here.
I think it's it's a decent size.
So I'm just going to leave it.
Then if we look for some text and drag three pieces of text into the horizontal box.
Okay.
Once you've done that, select the first text and just call this apples.
Make sure this is available, is checked all the second text.
Just make it say the slash.
And then for this third text, call this max apples.
Make sure is aware of what is checked next.
If we head over to the graph and go over to the for loop section after this loop has finished running,
we are going to drag in our apples test.
Get this apple stacks and just drag copy and look for set text.
And we want this one set text and we're going to make this text, say the amount of apples that our
player character has.
So earlier we made a reference to our player character.
So dragging that reference.
And get them out Apple but they have.
So, look, we'll get apples and just hook this up here.
Then hook up completed.
After we do this, we're going to drag in our Mac's apples and just set the text of this.
And we'll set the text of this to be the maximum of apples that my player character has.
So I'll just drag in my player character reference again and get the maximum apples that they have.
And then hook this up here.
Then connect these two notes.
I'm just going to move this as a bit messy.
Then I want you to right click and add custom event and call this update.
Apple's.
And then connect this to the set text.
And basically, one of our character throws an apple.
We're going to call the update.
Apple's in our player widget blueprint.
So if we go back to our player blueprint.
After we set them out.
Apples that struck in our heart reference.
And called the update Apple's custom event.
So if I could compile and play on my screen, we can see I have five out of 30 apples and if I throw
one, my taps will update 294932951.
So my apple image looks kind of off.
So we go back to our player hard and just delete this image.
And with our vertical box and in the palette.
Let's look for another vertical box.
And if we just look for an image and just track it into our vertical box and for the image, select
the apple.
Just adjust it.
X and Y values with the value you're happy with.
Okay.
And I'm going to try and position my apple.
So it's kind of aligned with my text.
And if I go compile and play, I think that looks a bit better.
I'm also going to adjust my heart image because I think they're a bit big.
So if we go back to our heart blueprint, I'm just going to decrease it size.
And then let's let our heart empty and make it the same size.
So my hot fall is 51.
I'm just going to make it 51 by 51.
And I'll make this half empty.
51 by 51.
I never go compile and play.
My heart are a bit smaller, but I prefer that.